（未来の岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
これより 最終ミッション
I will now explain the parameters
オペレーションスクルドの
概要を説明する
of the final mission, Operation Skuld.
Change the result without changing established history.
確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変えろ
The past consists of Makise Kurisu, lying in pool of blood,
血まみれで倒れている
牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)と―
それを見た岡部倫太郎
and Okabe Rintarou seeing her there.
Change the past without changing that.
その確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変えるのだ
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）
父さん そこのドライバー取って
Dad, pass me that screwdriver.
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）
だから“父さん”って…
Why are you calling me "Dad"?
（鈴羽）いいから 早く
Just do it.
As I thought, we only get one more chance.
やっぱり あと１往復が限界かな
We don't have enough fuel for more than one trip to the past and back.
過去に行って戻ってくる
そのくらいの燃料しか残ってない
So you won't be able to return to the future?
（岡部）お前がいた未来には
帰れないということか？
I never planned to.
（鈴羽）
もともと戻る気がなかった
こっちで世界線を変えて
未来が変われば―
By changing the world line here
and thereby changing the future, I won't need to go back.
戻る必要はなかったから…
ただ…
But...
If I fail to change it, I'll have to stay here.
もし 変えることが
できなければ―
私は ここで生きていくことになる
ずっと後悔したまま…
Regretting it, forever.
Don't be stupid!
（岡部）
何をバカなことを言っている
Uncle...
（鈴羽）おじさん
（岡部）おじさんではない
I'm not your uncle.
I am Hououin Kyouma, mad scientist,
我が名は 鳳凰院凶真(ほうおういんきょうま)
狂気の
マッドサイエンティストにして―
and the man who will destroy the world's power structure.
世界の支配構造を破壊する男
失敗など ありえん
Failure is not an option.
うん 分かった　信じるよ
Got it. I believe you.
We commence Operation Skuld.
（岡部）
これより オペレーション
スクルドを実行に移す
時は来たれり！
The time is now!
（岡部）
ああ… どこだ？
～
Where is it?
I know it was around here somewhere.
ここら辺に置いて
あったはずなのだが…
Achievement
Point
He made me laugh when he said, "The time is now,"
（橋田）
“時は来たれり！ キリッ”とか
しといて―
and then had to run to the lab because he forgot something.
忘れ物して
ラボに戻ってる件について…
（鈴羽）
早くしてよ　タイムマシン
あんまり長いあいだ―
Hurry up!
We can't leave the time machine there for too long.
あそこに置いとくわけには
いかないんだから
（岡部）ああ？
ん？
（橋田）サイリウムセイバー？
そんなもん 何するん？
The Cyalume Saber?
What are you going to do with that?
The sticky red fluid in its core is the key.
（岡部）重要なのは
この先端に仕掛けられている血のり
Huh? I didn't know that was there.
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）
へえー そんなのあったんだ
なるほど それを牧瀬紅莉栖の血に
見せるわけだね？
I understand.
You plan to substitute it for Makise Kurisu's blood.
Exactly.
いかにも
On July 28th, if I see
（岡部）７月28日の俺が
an unconscious Christina lying in a pool of blood,
血のりの上で気を失って倒れている
クリスティーナを発見すれば―
the past won't change.
確定した過去は変わらない
That's the idea behind Operation Skuld.
それがオペレーションスクルドの
意味するところ
I guess it makes sense, but...
（鈴羽）
確かに 理屈は合ってるけれど…
Doesn't it seem a little too easy?
（橋田）
でも なんか単純すぎね？
Future Okarin made it sound like a greater force was at work here.
15年後のオカリンは―
もっとデカい秘密が
ありそうな感じで―
話していたように思われ…
（岡部）フフフフッ
（橋田）ん？
Hououin Kyouma speaks even more dramatically
鳳凰院凶真は―
作戦が単純であればあるほど
大げさに言う男だ
when a plan is simple.
フフフフッ バカめ
The fool...
I see through his schemes!
すでに貴様のやり方は
すべて見抜いているのだ！
感心していいところなのかな
I don't know whether to be impressed or not.
（岡部）アーハハハハッ
（橋田）全俺が泣いた
Mad scientist fail.
Hey...
（まゆり）ねえ オカリン
Okarin?
Did that Kurisu person sit here?
紅莉栖さんって
ここに座ってなかった？
With you?
（まゆり）オカリンと…
（岡部）まゆり？
Mayuri...
（まゆり）ダル君と
いつも一生懸命 話ししてて…
She'd get really excited and talk to Daru.
And Mayushii wouldn't really understand,
まゆしぃは よく分からないけど
なんか夢中で話してて…
but they were having lots of fun.
And you two fought constantly,
オカリンと紅莉栖さんは
よくケンカするんだけど―
きっと とっても仲良くて…
but really, you were good friends.
Mayushii, what are you talking about?
（橋田）
まゆ氏 何 言っとるん？
Makise Kurisu is a scientific genius.
牧瀬紅莉栖って 天才科学者だお
こんなラボに来るはずないって…
She would never come to a lab like this.
It's weird, right?
うん 変だよね
Was it a dream?
夢なのかな
Maybe she possesses the Reading Steiner too?
もしかして この子にも
リーディング･シュタイナーが？
いや そんな力はない
No, she doesn't.
But somewhere inside, she remembers
（岡部）
でも どこかで覚えてるんだ
what happened in the other world lines.
別の世界線であったことを
誰でも 心のどこかで…
Everyone does, somewhere in their hearts.
Kurisu did everything she could to save Mayuri.
紅莉栖は まゆりを助けるために
全力を尽くしてくれた
Mayuri... No, all of us can be here now
まゆりが… いや 俺たちが
今ここに立っているのは―
because of Kurisu.
紅莉栖のおかげなんだ
（橋田）え？
Hey, Okarin? Do you like Kurisu?
（まゆり）ねえ オカリン
紅莉栖さんのこと 好き？
あ…
Christina is my assistant, my dear friend,
クリスティーナは
俺の助手であり―
大切な仲間であり―
and very special to me.
そして 特別な存在だ
そっか
I understand.
And she's in love with me too.
（岡部）それに あいつが
俺にホレているという事情もある
No way! Okarin gets a real girlfriend?
（橋田）ウソッ！
まさかのリア充展開
（まゆり）じゃあ 絶対助けなきゃ
Then you have to save her,
no matter what.
何があっても…
あ…
You must save her!
（まゆり）絶対 助けなきゃ
ああ
Yeah.
うん
Yup.
（橋田）んんんー
Be sure to bring her back!
（まゆり）きっと帰ってきてね
紅莉栖さんを連れて…
I will.
当たり前だ
（橋田）あっ あの 阿万音氏
Hey, um... Miss Amane...
If you're really my daughter,
僕の娘っていうのが本当だとすると
僕の嫁は？
who was my wife?
それは秘密にしておく
I'll keep that a secret.
Again?
（岡部）またか
（鈴羽）ん？
え？
Let's go!
（岡部）行くぞ
We've managed to arrive at exactly the same time as before.
（鈴羽）
さっきと全く同時刻に到達できた
The rest is up to you.
あとは おじさん次第だよ
Understood.
（岡部）分かってる
Just leave the Cyalume Saber where I asked you to.
サイリウムセイバーを
例の場所に置いといてくれ
On it.
任せて
（岡部）確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変える
Change the result without changing the established past.
For that to work...
そのためには…
this is where I begin.
まずは ここだ
I don't know the overall effect,
因果関係は分からない
but if I get the metal Upa here,
だが ここで俺が
メタルうーぱを出してしまえば―
it diminishes the odds of any metal ending up in that folder.
あの封筒に金属が紛れ込む
可能性は低くなる
（岡部）やはり…
I thought so.
There aren't many left of this series,
（まゆり）このシリーズ
あんまり残ってないのに―
まゆしぃは 100円玉を
切らしちゃっているのです
and Mayushii's out of 100 yen coins!
Don't be a spoiled little girl, Mayuri.
（過去の岡部）
甘ったれるな まゆり
たとえ 幼なじみであっても
カネは貸さん
Even though I've known you since we were kids, I'm not lending you money.
（まゆり）えーっ
（岡部）フフフフッ
I'll teach you how harsh life can be.
お前に今
人生の厳しさを教えてやろう
（まゆり）あ…
（まゆり）うーぱだよ！
It's an Upa!
レアなのか？
Is it rare?
It's not rare, but isn't it cute?
レアじゃないけどね
すごくカワイイでしょ？
Okay, next...
（岡部）よし 次
（牧瀬紅莉栖）あっ すみません
I'm sorry!
（岡部）紅莉栖…
Kurisu.
（紅莉栖）え？
どうして私の名前を？
How do you know my name?
Have we met somewhere before?
どこかでお会いしましたっけ？
（岡部）紅莉栖…
Kurisu...
Are you listening—
聞いてま… あっ
何なんです？
質問に答えてください
What's wrong with you?
Answer me.
俺は…
I...
I'm going to save you.
俺は お前を助ける
（館内放送のチャイム）
Professor Nakabachi's press conference
（案内放送）
これより８階ホールにて
中鉢(なかばち)博士の会見が開かれます
will now begin in the eighth floor hall.
（紅莉栖）待って！ 待ちなさい！
Wait!
Wait a second!
（案内放送）
これより８階ホールにて…
（岡部）まさか 自分で自分を
演じることになるとはな…
I never imagined I'd have to pretend to be myself.
Kurisu picked up the Upa that Mayuri dropped?
まゆりの落とした うーぱを
紅莉栖が拾っていたのか？
Mayushii
だが うーぱが
金属でなくなった以上―
But since it isn't metal,
that folder will burn in the airplane accident.
中鉢の封筒は 放っておいても
飛行機の事故で焼けるはず
All that's left is getting rid of Nakabachi
あとは 中鉢を追い払い―
and finding a chance to knock out Kurisu.
隙を見て 紅莉栖を気絶させれば…
あっ…
血のりが固まってる？
The liquid dried up?
そうか 長いあいだ
血のり部分は使わずにいたから―
That's right!
I haven't used it for such a long time
that air got in and dried out the liquid.
空気に触れて凝固し… あっ！
（中鉢博士）何の用だ？
What do you want?
I wanted you to read this, Daddy.
（紅莉栖）あのね これを…
Think...
（岡部）考えろ 考えるんだ
Think!
There must be something.
何かあるはずだ 何か！
Something!
Think!
考えろ
Getting rid of Nakabachi won't be difficult.
中鉢を追い払うのは
難しいことじゃない
But the blood will be problematic.
問題は血のりだ
If there was just something I could substitute...
血のりの
代わりになる物さえあれば…
（中鉢博士）黙れ！
（紅莉栖）ああっ
Shut up!
（中鉢博士）よくも盗むなどと…
How dare you call it stealing?
That's it!
（岡部）そうだ！
Stop!
（岡部）やめろ！
Who are you?
（中鉢博士）誰だ？ 貴様は
（岡部）フフフフッ
A man who desires chaos.
混沌(こんとん)を望み
世界の支配構造を破壊する者
One who will destroy the world's power structure,
and the man who will destroy your ambitions.
そして お前の野望を打ち砕く者
Would you like to know my name?
聞きたいか？
I am...
我が名は―
鳳凰院
Hououin Kyouma!
凶真！
何をわけの分からないことを…
What nonsense are you talking about?
You're that kid!
お前 さっきのガキだな？
I get it.
なるほど そういうことか
So that's how it is.
You worked together to ruin my press conference...
貴様ら 示し合わせて―
私の会見を
台なしにしようとしたんだな？
ハハハッ
そうか そういうことか
I see. So that's how it is.
フフッ フフフッ フフッ
Daddy...
パパ
逃げて！
Run!
No!
（岡部）断る！
（紅莉栖）え？
What's wrong?
どうした？
Why did you bring that knife?
そのナイフは
何のために持っているんだ？
（中鉢博士）な… なんだと！
What did you say?
ポーズだけか？
Are you scared?
Do my godlike powers terrify you?
この神に等しい力を持つ俺に
恐れをなしたか？
D-Don't insult me!
ふ… ふざけるな！
さあ どうした？
震えているぞ 怖いのか？
Come on. You're shaking.
Are you scared?
How long will you insult me?
どこまで この私を
愚弄するつもりだ？
In the end, you're just a small, pathetic man.
（岡部）結局 貴様は
その程度の男なのだ
A man too small to appreciate his own daughter's talent can't kill me.
実の娘の有能さを喜べないなど―
貴様には この俺を
殺すことはできない
Never!
絶対に！
Ever!
絶対にな！
（岡部）あっ…
そ… そんな
N-No way.
（岡部）うっ… ぐっ
そんな… ウソ…
No...
This can't be happening.
ハハッ　ざ… ざまあみろ
Th-That's what you get...
Calm down.
（岡部）落ち着け
あと… 少し
Almost there...
（岡部）よ… よくも
How dare you?
殺して…
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you!
殺してやる！
（中鉢博士）あああ…
（中鉢博士）ただで済むと思うな！
You won't get away with this!
ハッ
う… 動いちゃダメ
D-Don't move!
Lie down. I'll call an ambulance.
横になって！
今 救急車を呼ぶから！
Hello?
もしもし 救急ですか？
すぐ来てほしいんです！
Is this emergency services?
I need someone here now!
I...
Someone is stabbed!
（岡部）俺は…
言った… だろ？
I told you...
俺は お前を 助ける
I'm going to save you.
（紅莉栖）あっ
うっ ぐああああ！
This is, without doubt,
（岡部）これは
間違いなく 俺が見た
the Kurisu I saw.
紅莉栖だ
Uncle...
（鈴羽）おじさん
Goodbye.
（岡部）さよなら
（岡部）あっ 待て
（鈴羽）えっ？
Wait.
Could you just wait a minute?
（岡部）ちょっとだけ
待ってくれないか？
（鈴羽）そんなこと
している場合じゃないよ
We don't have time!
You'll bleed out.
おじさん このままじゃ…
頼む
Please.
（過去の岡部）
おい 誰かいるのか？
Hey, is someone there?
Good luck.
（岡部）頑張れよ
You're about to begin the longest,
これから始まるのは
人生で一番長く―
most important three weeks of your life.
一番大切な３週間だ
（鈴羽）もう無茶しすぎだよ
バカにも程がある
You went too far!
Even stupidity has its limits!
What are you talking about?
（岡部）バカとはなんだ…
計画どおりだろ？
The plan succeeded.
All I can do is stop the bleeding.
（鈴羽）
簡単な止血しかしてないから
戻ったら すぐに病院行ってね
When we get back, you'll need to go to a hospital.
This'll be hard, but try to hang on.
きついと思うけど
なんとか耐えてね
Here we go.
いくよ
（岡部）ううっ ううっ
This is...
これは…
Yeah.
（鈴羽）
うん シュタインズ･ゲートは
誰も知らない世界線
No one knows what'll happen in the Steins Gate world line.
Suzuha...
（岡部）鈴羽
But if your theory is correct, the paper will burn,
so the time machine arms race won't come to pass.
（鈴羽）でも
おじさんの理論が正しければ―
論文は焼け
タイムマシン開発競争は起きず―
Neither will World War III.
第３次世界大戦も起こらない
I can't stay,
私は一緒にいることはできない
だから 先にお礼を言っておくね
so I'll say thank you now.
フフッ
ありがとう
Thank you.
I'll see you in seven years.
また会おうね ７年後に…
Card: To Okarin
Card: For Okabe Rintarou-sama
（まゆり）
うんしょ うんしょ
うんしょ
Okabe
Rintarou-sama
オカリーン
Okarin!
あれ？
（中鉢博士）
人類の未来に
That paper would've altered mankind's future.
It was a paper for constructing a time machine!
タイムマシンに関わる
重大な論文が―
And it's gone... Burned up!
燃えてしまったんだ！
His words were unclear,
（アナウンサー）などと
意味不明であり
and the Russian government denied everything.
ロシア政府は亡命を
受け入れない方針…
Was Okarin here, Ruka?
（まゆり）るか君
オカリンが来たって？
I missed him!
入れ違いになっちゃった
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）
あっ そのとき…
When he came by...
ん？
This badge identifies you as Lab Member 006.
（岡部）
ラボメンナンバー
００６の証しだ
（るか）えっ？
僕 いつラボメンに？
When did I become a lab member?
Those memories may rest in your other life.
（岡部）その記憶は―
あるいは前世まで
さかのぼるかもしれんな
へえー
What are these characters?
何だろう？ この文字
Kyouma?
（フェイリス）凶真？
さっきまでいたニャ
He was just here.
やっぱり？
I knew it.
Did you get something, Feyris?
フェリスちゃん
何か もらわなかった？
ん？ そういえば…
Now that you mention it...
（岡部）
ラボメンナンバー
００７のピンバッジだ
This badge is for Lab Member 007.
助けが欲しいときは
それを握りしめ―
When you desire my aid, hold the badge and say,
"La Yohda Stasella." Just like that.
〝ラ ヨーダ
スタセッラ〞と―
唱えるがいい
ほう
（天王寺裕吾(てんのうじゆうご)）あ？
Okabe was just here.
岡部なら さっきまで
ここにいたのによ
Big Sis Mayuri!
（天王寺 綯(なえ)）
まゆりおねえちゃん
（まゆり）
トゥットゥルー
綯ちゃん
Nae!
（まゆり）…と？
（天王寺）ああ
She'll be working here, from now on.
今日から ここで
バイトすることになった
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）
桐生萌郁です
I'm Kiryuu Moeka.
（天王寺）
綯が転んだところを
助けてもらってな
She helped Nae after she fell down.
She said she didn't have a job,
ちょうど 仕事もない
っつうから―
so she'll be working here.
うちで働いてもらうこと
になった
I'm Shiina Mayuri.
椎名まゆりです
She's really popular.
（天王寺）大人気だな
Okabe started hitting on her the minute he saw her.
岡部の野郎も―
会うなり
ナンパしやがってよ
Visit the lab whenever you like.
（岡部）いつでも
ラボを訪れるといい
～
（萌郁）あの…
Um...
Thank you.
ありがとう
（まゆり）
トゥットゥルー
おかえリン
Oh, come in!
Do "oh, come in" and "Okarin" sound that similar?
（橋田）
“おかえり”と“オカリン”を
合体させたん？
Yup!
（まゆり）うん
オカリンは？
Where's Okarin?
He said he was going shopping.
（橋田）うん ちょっと
買い物 行ってくるって
I see.
（まゆり）そっか
（まゆり）おお！
（橋田）ん？
あっ これ？
ラボメンの証しだってさ
These?
He said they're lab member badges.
Lab Member 002 and 003!
ラボメンナンバー００２と００３！
いつの間に ラボメン
そんなに増えたん？
When did we get so many lab members?
He said they go up to 008.
００８まであるって
言ってたけど…
Okarin's "O."
Ｏはオカリンでしょ？
Shiina, Hashida, Urushibara, Feyris...
椎名　橋田　漆原　フェリス
ん？ ＭとＫとＡって？
Who are "M," "K," and "A"?
（橋田）さあ
Dunno.
He had another one that he put in a box.
あっ あと もう１個
箱の中にしまっていったお
Lab Member 008 will arrive in seven years.
（岡部）
ラボメンナンバー００８は
７年後に現れる
More fantasies?
（橋田）また 妄想っすか？
It's an inevitable future.
（岡部）必然だ ダルのな
Your inevitable future.
Mine?
僕の？
Seven years...
（まゆり）７年後…
It'll be fun.
楽しみだな
どんなラボメンなんだろう
Who do you think it'll be?
７年後って 想像もできないお
Seven years? I can't imagine.
But I don't think the lab will change,
でもね ラボは変わらないと思うよ
no matter how many years go by.
何年たっても ずっと…
Where are you now?
（岡部）お前は今
どこにいるのだろう？
アメリカの研究機関で
論文を書いているだろうか？
Are you writing a paper in an American research lab?
Are you working all night on some experiment?
確かめたいことがあって
徹夜で実験をしているだろうか？
You may still be thinking of your father.
もしかしたら 父のことで
まだ悩んでいるかもしれない
俺と過ごした３週間を
お前は覚えていない
You don't remember the three weeks we spent together.
だが それでいい
But that's okay.
Right now, you're breathing, speaking,
お前が 今どこかで
息をして 声を出して―
何かを一生懸命 考えている
and thinking your hardest about something.
それで十分だ
That's enough.
俺と同じ世界を―
You're watching the same world I am,
未来が まだ分からない
この世界を―
this world with its unknown future.
どこかで一緒に見ているのだから…
（紅莉栖）やっと 会えた
I finally found you.
あなたを探していたんです
I was looking for you.
I wanted to thank you for saving me.
助けてくれた お礼を言いたくて…
（岡部）俺だ
なぜ彼女が ここにいる？
It's me.
Why is she here?
What?
何？
Because I protected her?
俺が守れだと？
You're flattering me.
やれやれ
勝手なことを言ってくれる
Well, if that's its choice.
まあいい
それが選択だというのなら…
El Psy Congroo.
エル･プサイ･コングルゥ
El Psy?
（紅莉栖）エルプサイ？
We meet again, Christina!
（岡部）
また会えたな クリスティーナ
I told you I'm not Christina, and I'm not your assistant.
いや だから―
私はクリスティーナでも
助手でもないと…
あ… あれ？
Huh?
Welcome my assistant, Makise Kurisu.
ようこそ 我が助手 牧瀬紅莉栖
No, Christina.
いや クリスティーナ
No one knows what the future holds.
（岡部）
未来のことは 誰にも分からない
It has infinite potential,
だからこそ
この再会が意味するように―
as this encounter makes clear.
無限の可能性があるんだ
This is the choice of Steins Gate.
これが シュタインズ･ゲートの
選択だよ